Daniel Ofori



loyedan@gmail.com \(+233545290372 \) Accra, Ghana

Data Analyst | Laboratory Technologist | Volunteer

Summary

Daniel Ofori is a resilient Laboratory Scientist with certifications from Accra Technical University. Research and Data Analysis with SPSS, Graphpad Prism and Excel has allowed success in academic/industrial settings to fulfil projects in a timely manner.

Experience

Lead Researcher

Jan 2020 - Present (2 years 7 months +)

ZMART LABS

Accra, Ghana

Duties:

- Developed research materials for both industrial and academic setting.
- Partnered with students and lecturers in Pharmacy, Engineering and the Health sector to analyze and produce comprehensive reports.
- Proficient in Survey Analysis as a major go to statistical instrument for social science experiments.

Quality Control Intern

Feb 2021 - Mar 2021 (2 months)

New Global Pharmaceuticals

Odorkor, Accra

Duties:

- Disintegration and Dissolution of tablets and capsule, Friability and Hardness of a tablet with Temperature and humidity checks, Leak test, pH and specific gravity of syrups was carried out.
- Assaying of Active Pharmaceutical Ingredient in raw materials, during granulation process to conform with the stated labelling amount was performed
- Line clearance of personnel, environment, equipment was checked during my shift.

Laboratory Technologist

National Cardiothoracic Center
(National Service)

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019 (1 year 3 months)

Korle-Bu, Accra

Duties:

- Taking of patient samples (blood and urine) for analysis.
- Running of hematology tests, serology tests, electrolyte tests, and Urinalysis.
- Performing basic laboratory tests (B/F, VDRL, H-Pylori, Widal, Retro)
- Running of Urine chemistry, sensitivity tests, Blood chemistry, Microscopy.

Laboratory Technician Intern

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016 (3 months)

Ridge Regional Hospital

Ridge, Accra

Duties:

Phlebotomy.

- Performing basic laboratory tests (B/F, VDRL, H. Pylori, Widal, Retro).
- Urine chemistry and sensitivity.
- Microbiological tests (Urine, stool sample, blood and sputum).

Science and ICT Teacher

Jul 2015 - Sep 2015 (3 months)

Jamverson Academy

Duty:

I handled students from primary 6 to JHS 2 on Science and ICT.

Education

Bachelor of Technology - (BTECH) Analytical Chemistry

Sep 2019 - Nov 2021



Accra Technical University

Accra, Ghana

Thesis: The Effect of Moringa Oleifera and Pasteurization on The Shelf Life of Ice-Kenkey, A Traditional Maize Beverage in Ghana.

Higher National Diploma - (HND) Science Laboratory Technology Sep 2015 – 2018

Accra Technical University

Accra, Ghana

Thesis: Antimicrobial Assessment of Momordica Charantia on Staphylococcus Aureus and Streptococcus Pyogenes.

WASSCE, Science

Jan 2012 - Jan 2015

Odorgonno Senior High

Accra, Ghana

Activities and societies - English and Debate Team and Scripture Union

Licenses & Certifications



Bachelor of Technology (BTECH) in Analytical Chemist

Accra Technical University

National Service

Ghana National Service Scheme



Higher National Diploma (HND) Laboratory Technologist

Accra Technical University



FUNDAMENTALS OF GRANT WRITING

Young African Leaders Initiative

Technical Skills

- ✓ Cybersecurity (OSINT Tools)
- ✓ IT Operations (Linux, Windows) OS)
- ✓ Python (Programming) Language) – Introductory exposure

- ✓ Data Analysis (SPSS, Graphpad Prism, Microsoft Excel)
- ✓ Google suite
- ✓ Drug Development
- ✓ Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS)

Non-Technical Skills

- ✓ Product Quality
- ✓ Management
- ✓ Health & Safety

- ✓ Reporting & Analysis
- ✓ Good Manufacturing Practice (GMP)

DANIEL OFORI 3

✓ Communication

√ Teaching

Honors & Awards

UBA Foundation National Essay Competition

UBA Group 2014

 Named as one of the 12 finalists of a National Essay Competition for Senior Secondary Schools in Ghana.

Memberships / Affiliations

√	lοT	Network Hub

✓ Owasp Ghana

✓ Linux Accra User Group

✓ AfricaHackon GH (AH_233)

Referees

Mr. Albert Akorli

Laboratory Technologist

National Cardiothoracic Centre

0557313896

Mrs. Elizabeth Banaska

Quality Assurance Manager

New Global Pharmaceuticals

0573400916